

www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran	in
alporan.github.io/blog	
alporan@windowslive.com	$\searrow$
90 537 513 45 29	Ö

# **PROFILE**

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing and maintaining software systems. Quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Strong problem solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-manage during personal projects.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Şekerbank T.A.Ş.

Senior Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Main responsibilities;

- Developing applications by using Java, Spring Framework, and Agile practices for the middleware utilized by digital channels (Web/Mobile Branches, Call Center, IVR, etc.)
- Taking part in architectural design of middleware layer as part of the microservices transformation.
- Maintaining legacy JSP-Servlet based Java EE web application.
- Bugfixing and troubleshooting.

### **BilgeAdam Technologies**

Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Working as a Consultant Software Engineer at Şekerbank T.A.Ş.

#### **Turkish Airlines**

Software Engineer, 2017-2020

Main responsibilities;

- Developing mainframe applications for reservation, ticketing, and DCS systems using Java, Spring Framework, IBM High-Level Assembler, and Agile practices.
- Migrating mainframe applications to open systems as part of architectural transformation projects.
- Maintenance of codebase and database records.
- Bugfixing and troubleshooting.
- Automating manual tasks and test cases with Python Programming Language.
- Providing support for open system teams utilizing mainframe programs.
- Conducting code reviews.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Sakarya University - Information Technologies

Turkey, Sakarya

Master of Science, 2018-2019

#### Istanbul Technical University - Electronics and Communications Engineering

Turkey, Istanbul *Bachelor of Science, 2011-2015* 

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Gateway Application for Digital Channel Front-end Transformation**

Backend For Frontend architecture implementation to address the needs of a new view layer developed with React. The implementation serves services of JSP/Servlet-based web application as RESTful APIs.

### Personal Webpage/Blog

Static webpage for presenting my portfolio and blogging.

**Tools:** Jekyll, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Link:** https://alporan.github.io/blog

#### **Clinic Appointment Application**

Implementing CRUD operations for simple clinic appointment application.

Tools: MySQL, Angular, Java, Spring Boot

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app

#### Attachmate Extra! X-treme Macro Interface

Interface for developing utility programs and macros with Python programming language for Extra! X-treme terminals

Tools: Python, PyQt5, Extra! X-treme API

Link: <a href="https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface">https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface</a>

#### **Blazing Fruits**

Android game checks multitasking and hand-eye coordination.

Tools: Java, Android Studio, libGDX Library

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing\_fruits

### An Indoor Localization Algorithm On FPGA

Multiple RF reader modules were localized by using received signal strength value from stationary RFID tags. Localization algorithm was implemented on an FPGA.

Tools: Verilog, C++, FPGAs

Link: https://web.itu.edu.tr/~orssi/thesis/2015/AlpOran\_bit.pdf

# **SKILLS**

# **Programming Languages & Frameworks**

- Java
- Spring Framework
- Spring Boot
- Jakarta EE
- IBM High-Level Assembler Language
- SQL
- Python
- Hibernate
- JUnit

#### **Tools**

- Git
- GitHub / BitBucket
- Relational Databases
- JIRA
- CA Endevor SCM
- CA Clarity PPM

# **LANGUAGES & TEST SCORES**

**Turkish**: Native or bilingual proficiency **English**: Full professional proficiency

IELTS (International English Language Testing System), Nov 2015

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

Overall Score: 7.5/9

TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), Jul 2015

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

Total Score: 92/120